Good evening everyone.
各位觀眾
Good evening everyone, welcome to Ignite Taipei 2.
各位觀眾， 歡迎你們來到這次的Ignite台北
I am really honored to see so many people here tonight.
然後很高興這次有很多人來聽我們的演講 我真的感到非常榮幸，大家都可以來
Before we begin,
然後呢，在大家還沒開始之前
I would like to demonstrate an Ignite talk
我想做一個算是小小的示範的Ignite Talk
to let everyone know what Ignite is.
然後呢，也可以讓你們知道什麼是Ignite
Let’s go!
好，那要開始囉
I am your host tonight, Tifi.
大家好，我是這次的主辦人及主持人劉芝庭，我叫Tifi
I am English major at the Fu Jen University.
我現在就讀輔仁大學英文系大三
Nice to meet you all
然後，很高興認識各位
Now allow me to introduce you Ignite Taipei
現在開始我要先講一個小小的演講， 讓大家知道什麼是Ignite
First, our slogan is:
第1， 我想要介紹Ignite 台北的宗旨
Enlighten us, but make it quick.
Enlighten us, but make it quick.
We want to be inspired instantly.
迅速且效率的啟發你我__
If anyone is not familiar with the word 'ignite' It means to set something on fire
要是有人不知道ignite的單字的話， ignite就是點燃的意思
We want to light up our inspiration instantly
所我們希望在短時間內能點燃你的靈感
Many people have asked me What is the difference between Ignite and TED?
然後呢，很多人問我到底 Ignite和TED不一樣的地方在哪裡
Don't they both host many lectures? Are the lectures different?
他們的差異在哪裡 不都是很多演講嗎？
Well, does anyone not heard of TED?
有人不知道TED是什麼嗎？有誰不知道TED嗎？
The first difference is time control.
第1， 就是時間
An Ignite talk has only 5 minutes.
Ignite台北每一個演講都只有五分鐘
With 20 Powerpoint slides
只有20張投影片以自動化呈現
Each auto-advance in 15 seconds
15秒自動化呈現
So it only takes one evening to host an Ignite event
然後Ignite台北只有一個晚上的時間
All the many talks will fit into one evening
所以全部的演講就會 在一個晚上內有所有的內容
No matter you like it or want to fall asleep
所以不管你覺得很無聊或想睡覺
5 minutes will past fast
沒關係五分鐘很快就過了
If you like the lectures
要是你覺得很有趣的話呢， 那請你好好把握這五分鐘
Please make good use of the 5 minutes
因為所有人都只有五分鐘
It's not much
沒有多，就五分鐘
The second difference is speakers.
再來呢，講者
Does anybody not know who this person is?
應該沒有人不知道這位先生是誰吧
Who doesn't know?
誰不知道？
He is Steve Jobs, founder of Apple.
這位先生是Steve Jobs，蘋果的創辦人
And the person on the right? Anonymous.
那右邊這位各位可能就沒有什麼人知道了
What I want to say is, Everybody can be a speaker at Ignite.
所以我想說的是，任何人都可以是講者
If you are interested in sharing
只要你有興趣，你有東西想要跟大家分享
You can come up here and speak.
任何人都可以是個講者
Even for Steve Jobs would get just 5 minutes
就算Steve Jobs來我們也只給他五分鐘啦
The third difference, topics.
再來，是題目
TED focuses mainly on technology, entertainment and design
TED主要是關於科技、娛樂、設計
All those three topics.
TED主要是圍繞這三個主題
But Ignite welcomes all kinds of topics
但是呢，Ignite台北的主題可以是任何東西
Any topic,
什麼任何東西
such as, how to perform well on tests,
像是如何在一次考試拿到高分，是猜題猜得比較高分，
or how to communicate more efficiently
或是如何讓你的溝通更順暢
Whatever you like
任何題目都可以
So Ignite Taipei wants to enlighten people
所以呢，Ignite台北到底想告訴大家什麼呢
To inspire people in life
我們希望能點燃你生命裡的靈感
From things they have not expected or experienced before
你意想不到、沒有經歷過的東西
To inspire you through the talks
希望能從演講裡點燃你生命裡的靈感
We organized Ignite in Taipei because...
所以呢，到底為什麼Ignite會辦在台北
Anybody have an idea?
大家有任何的想法嗎？
Okay, I'll tell you.
好吧我來告訴大家好了
First, we want drinks.
第1， 要有飲料
We think people who like beer or coke Are those who like the relaxed atmosphere
我們認為喝啤酒、喝可樂的人， 都喜歡在輕鬆快樂的環境
We can have fun and be happy
大家不要那麼嚴肅啊、隨便坐啊、開心就好
And attend the event with a good mood
我們希望大家可以以輕鬆愉快的心情來參加Ignite演講
Second, we welcome people from everywhere.
再來呢，我們可能有來自台北或是各個地方的朋友
We want you to join us
我們都希望你可以加入我們
Regardless of your age, gender or background
不管是年齡、背景、性別
We give you something if you show up tonight
只要你今天來了，我們都希望可以帶給你一些不同的東西
Third, we want to create connections.
再來呢，我想創造一些連結
At Ignite, you meet people from different walks of life.
在這裡你會遇到和你同樣性質同樣背景的人
You brainstorm together and create new thoughts
你們會產生不同的想法、一起腦力激盪
Thus the connections are formed
我們希望在這過程中能創造更多的連結
And we can get to know more people
大家可以彼此認識
Last, Ignite Taipei is special because We have both English and Chinese versions
再來，Ignite台北和其他分會比較 不一樣的地方是我們有英文版和中文版
We had Ignite Taipei 1 in English this June
英文版是在今年(2011)六月所舉辦的Ignite台北一
Ignite Taipei 2 in Chinese
這次Ignite台北二是中文版
And the coming up Ignite Taipei 3 in English this December
接下來還有Ignite台北三，是在今年十二月
We will host Ignite events constantly in the future
之後我們會定期舉辦Ignite台北
The next ignite will be in English, and I hope you all will attend that as well!
接下來的Ignite台北三是英文版的， 但是也希望大家可以報名參加
Besides Ignite Taipei, there's also Ignite Seattle, Ignite Singapore...
除了Ignite台北之外，還有西雅圖、新加坡
Ignite is everywhere
Ignite散布在各個地方
So you have a lot of opportunities to see Ignite
所以大家有機會可以體驗Ignite， 或是更local的一些東西
Before we start, I would like to remind you to switch your phones to silent
在Ignite台北開始之前， 我希望大家可以將手機轉為震動或是關機
And to speak at low volume
講話也請小聲一點，以免影響其他觀眾
Please follow the above two requirements
請大家注意以上兩點
And, please watch your little matches
最後也請大家注意旁邊的小火柴
Once you hear something interesting
只要一聽到自己有興趣或是感興趣的東西
or something new
或是自己從來沒想過的
Light them up
就請點燃你的小火柴
To have a flame, and make it into a big fire
讓你心目中的靈感火種發芽， 然後再蔓延成一個熊熊大火
You can contact us by this email address
這是我們的聯絡方式，Ignite台北
If you are interested in being a speaker to share
你有興趣或是想要成為我們的夥伴， 或是有興趣想要分享的話
Send us an email
請寄信給我們
And we also welcome your advice
我們很歡迎各位的一些想法
So, nice meeting you all tonight
最後我們很高興今天大家能來參加
We are the organizers tonight
我們是這次的主辦人
Thank you for coming, have a great night! Thank you!
謝謝大家來參加， 也祝大家有個美好的夜晚，謝謝！